"This play is related to specific characters, institutions, and groups It has nothing to do with the case and is purely fictitious. We hereby inform you"
"本剧与特定人物 机构 团体 案件无关 纯属虚构 特此告知"
Why did you come here without contacting me?
你怎么没联络我就来了
don't do that
你不要那么做
what's wrong with you
你是怎么了
Blindly asking me not to do anything
没头没脑的要我别做什么
Don't marry Li Douxue
你别跟李斗学结婚
I'm not here to make you angry
我不是来跟你闹脾气
Asking why you didn’t marry him and me
问你为什么跟他 不跟我结婚
Anyway, don’t marry Li Douxue
总之你别跟李斗学结婚
I already told him to wash his hands in a golden basin
我已经叫他金盆洗手了
That way I'll be by his side
那样我就会陪在他身边
He doesn't have a golden basin to wash his hands
他没有金盆洗手
He just concealed the facts of his crime
只是隐瞒了他的犯罪事实
Li Douxue is now...
李斗学现在…
In managing a larger criminal underworld organization
在管理更大型的黑道犯罪组织
Li Douxue
李斗学
Shouldn't you call him brother?
你不是应该叫他哥吗
Yeah
嗯
But he could also be a suspect
但他也可能成为嫌疑人
Wait until he really commits a crime
等他真的犯了罪
You can arrest him again and imprison him
你再把他抓去关
I will leave then too
到时我也会离开
You…
你…
Will definitely get hurt
一定会受伤
Even if I have to bear it, I will bear it alone
就算要承担 我也会一个人承担
You don't know what kind of person you are dealing with Falling in love?
你不知道你在跟怎么样的人 谈恋爱吗
Tetsuo, please don't worry about it anymore I learned this from Dou
哲雄 拜托你不要再管 我跟斗学的事了
Otherwise it will be you who suffers
否则痛苦的会是你
Hello
喂
It's me Ruzhen
是我 汝珍
I was threatened again today
我今天又被威胁了
I really want to die
我真的好想死
Ruzhen
汝珍
Team Leader Wu
吴组长
Yes Please tell me
是 您请说吧
I have something that has nothing to do with my country or nation.
我有件和国家民族无关
But it's important to my family
但对我的家人来说很重要的事
Please go and help me with a troublesome thing
请你去帮我办一件麻烦的事
don't let anyone know
别让任何人知道
Just go by yourself
你自己去就好
I think the deputy chief's stability
我认为次长的安定
It is the stability of the country
就是国家的安定
Please feel free to order me
请尽管吩咐我吧
thank you
谢谢你
I need you by my side all my life
我这辈子都需要你在身旁
I heard my mother say
我听我妈妈说了
you are my biological father
您是我的亲生父亲
Really?
是吗
You must be surprised
你一定很惊讶吧
(Episode 10) Yes
(第10集) 对
I want to be with your mother all my life
我想一辈子跟你妈妈在一起
It's not your mother's fault
不是你妈妈的错
i know
我知道
But…
不过…
I want to keep the name Cui
我想保留崔这个姓
hope for your understanding
望您谅解
Also
还有
I have a request
我有一个请求
Please learn from Li Dou
请跟李斗学
sever ties
断绝关系
I will also sever ties with him
我也会跟他断绝关系
Because he knows the secret of your murder?
因为他知道你杀过人的秘密吗
He's a good hunting dog for me
他对我来说是只好用的猎犬
Please find another hound
请您找别的猎犬吧
Why do you care so much about Li Douxue?
你为什么这么在意李斗学
Because he is a criminal
因为他是罪犯
And I am...
而我是…
A person who specializes in catching criminals
专门抓罪犯的人
Aren't you friends?
你们不是朋友吗
You even helped him
你还帮过他
At least I can distinguish between public and private affairs
我至少公私分明
If the deputy chief is not willing to learn from Li Dou Cut off ties…
如果次长不愿意和李斗学 断绝关系…
If I don't want to...
如果我不愿意…
I will punish you according to law
我就会依法办您
I mean it
我是真心的
I'll consider it
我会考虑看看的
scared me
吓我一跳
Hello
喂
What time is it now? Are you still awake?
现在都几点了 你还不睡
can't you sleep
你睡不着吗
are you waiting for a call
你在等电话吗
You quarreled with Douxue again
你又跟斗学吵架啦
Yoko, you are so annoying
阳子 你好烦
Go back to your sleep
快回去睡你的觉
I need to go to the toilet
我要去上厕所
And…
还有…
Are you more annoyed?
你更烦好不好
I really hope she gets married soon
真希望她快点嫁出去
Do you want to learn?
斗学吗
what happened
到底发生了什么事
Is it related to the news just now?
跟刚才那则新闻有关吗
My dad passed away
我爸去世了
what did you say
你说什么
Uncle?
伯父吗
Yeah
嗯
How could uncle...
伯父怎么会…
That's right
就是啊
Why is he here...
他怎么会在这里…
did you read it wrong
你有没有看错
Is he really his uncle?
真的是伯父吗
There is a father present...
现场有爸爸…
Cigarettes smoked every day
每天抽的烟
And the last time I was with him
还有我跟他最后一次
When we go to dinner together
一起去吃饭时
That restaurant…
那间餐厅…
The matchbox given
送的火柴盒
(Xinchuan Garden)
(新川花园)
So it must be dad right
所以应该是爸没错
How could it be
怎么会
How could...
怎么会…
I should...
我应该…
I told him to finish his meal before leaving.
叫他吃完饭再走的
I should keep him...
我应该留住他的…
Why didn't you say a word...
为什么一句话也没说…
If you don't go to work, where will you go?
你不去干活 跑去哪里了
Why is the back of your hand as rough as tree bark?
你的手背怎么跟树皮一样粗糙
Why are you like this suddenly?
你怎么会突然这样
Wife, thank you for your hard work.
老婆 真的辛苦你了
Oh my God, you finally understand.
天啊 你终于懂事啦
Then you should be nicer to me in the future
那你以后要对我好一点
No. Where are you going?
不是 你又要去哪里
It's time to eat
该吃饭了
Academic father
斗学的爸爸
It's time to eat...
该吃饭了…
Strange. Is that old man having an affair?
奇怪 那老头有外遇了吗
Why is it so worrying?
为什么这么让人操心
Mr. Li Douxue
李斗学先生
I'm from the Criminal Division of the Supreme Prosecutor's Office Prosecutor Park Ji-hwan
我是大检察厅刑事部的 朴志焕检察官
Now we have to use excessive violence and so on Relevant laws to arrest you
现在要以滥用暴力等 相关法律逮捕你
You have the right to exercise your right to remain silent
你有权行使缄默权
What you say may become Evidence presented against you
你说的话将来可能成为 对你不利的呈堂证供
arrest him Yes
逮捕他吧 是
Douxue
斗学
Big brother
大哥
get out of the way
让开
who are you
你们是什么人
what are you doing
你们在做什么
We're from the Supreme Prosecutor's Office
我们是从大检察厅来的
The underworld boss Li Douxue is currently being arrested.
现在正在逮捕黑道老大李斗学
what
什么
What are you talking about?
你们在胡说什么
He is a legitimate entrepreneur
他是合法的企业家
Yes, he has already washed his hands in a golden basin.
是啊 他早就金盆洗手了
You are his little brothers, right?
你们是他的小弟吧
Don't worry we'll meet again soon
别担心 我们很快就会再见面
At that time, you will also be investigated together.
到时你们也要一起接受调查
His father just died
他的爸爸才刚去世
You guys are going too far
你们太过分了
I was on official duty when my dad died.
我爸爸去世时我也在执行公务
Even though it was a few years ago
虽然是几年前的事了
come here
过来
you bastards
你们这些混蛋
my dad's cigarettes
我爸爸的烟
Don't worry, I will take good care of it for you
不用担心 我会帮你好好保管
Big brother…
大哥…
Douxue
斗学
let me go
放开我
Something unexpected happened. Prosecutor Choi took action.
出了点意外 崔检察官行动了
what
什么
Li Douxue was arrested just now
李斗学刚才被逮捕了
Prosecutor Choi did not arrest anyone personally
崔检察官没有亲自去抓人
Instead, let other prosecutors go so i didn't notice
而是让其他检察官去 所以我没注意到
what to do now
现在该怎么办
(Trustworthy Seoul Police)
(值得信任的首尔警察)
Brat, what crime have I committed?
臭小子 我犯了什么罪
Recruit quickly. Where is Wen Dongxiu hiding now?
快招出文东秀现在藏在哪里
I'll let you sleep well and comfortably
我就让你舒服地睡个好觉
I really don't know
我真的不知道
I don't know what you want me to say
不知道你要我说什么
I know you are boyfriend and girlfriend
我知道你们是男女朋友
How could you not know where he is?
你怎么可能不知道他在哪
We're not in that kind of relationship
我们不是那种关系
I'll ask you one last time
我再问你最后一次
Where is Wen Dongxiu?
文东秀在哪里
Your Loyalty Society...
你们忠义会…
Criminal records are really diverse.
犯罪前科还真是五花八门
It's like a department store with everything you need
简直像百货公司 应有尽有
Li Douxue
李斗学
You are their leader
你就是他们的首脑
Loyalty Association…
忠义会…
Just a simple friendship group
只是单纯的联谊团体
Is it possible that some members stole at ordinary gatherings?
难道在一般聚会上有成员盗窃
Is the organizer the mastermind of theft?
主办人就是盗窃首脑吗
what
什么
Triad groups and general gatherings
黑社会团体跟一般的聚会
Can it be compared?
能比吗
From now on I will exercise my right to remain silent
从现在起我要行使缄默权
(Lee Jong-ho)
(李钟昊)
No wonder this old man suddenly became so sensible
难怪这老头子突然变得这么懂事
Douxue?
斗学呢
Something happened to him and he needs to be investigated. Went to the prosecutor's office
他出了点事 需要去接受调查 去了检察厅
Where is Zhenyu?
贞玉呢
We've been asking around for her whereabouts.
我们已经在四处打听她的下落了
So…
所以…
Am I the only one left in this family?
这个家只剩我了吗
Sorry, aunt
对不起 伯母
(ID card Li Zhonghao)
(身分证 李钟昊)
Let's go quickly
我们快走吧
A studious father will be very lonely alone
斗学的爸爸一个人会很孤单
Why are you so cold?
你怎么这么冰
You must be cold
你一定很冷吧
Why don't you dress warmly?
怎么不穿暖一点
(Prosecutor Choi Cheol-woong)
(检察官 崔哲雄)
Tetsuo
哲雄啊
Let uncle hug you
让叔叔抱抱你吧
Uncle... I'm really proud of you
叔叔…真的很以你为荣
It doesn't matter if I'm not your father
我不当你的爸爸也无所谓
I really…
我真的…
I really won't regret it
我真的不会后悔
This is barley tea
这是薏仁茶
You drink it
你喝吧
After receiving a call from Dingchen
接到定辰的电话以后
I'm also surprised
我也很吃惊
It's because of dad
是因为爸
Or because of me
还是因为我
All
都是
Brother, you might not believe it
哥你也许不会相信
But I really like uncle
但我真的很喜欢叔叔
Sometimes…
有时…
He is better than my father
他比我爸爸
More like my real dad
更像我亲爸爸
The autopsy results are out
尸检结果出来了
He was hit and killed by a large car in a hit-and-run accident.
他是被肇事逃逸的大型车撞死的
I still can't contact Zhenyu.
应该还是联络不上贞玉
Auntie must be feeling very uncomfortable being alone right now.
阿姨现在一个人应该很难受
I helped you mediate a bit
我帮你斡旋了一下
You can finish the funeral first Come back and take the survey
你可以先办完丧事 再回来接受调查
You go back first
你先回去吧
Zhenyu
贞玉
Brother
哥
It's very hard in there, right?
在里面很辛苦吧
I didn't even know you were here
我都不知道你在这里
I keep looking for you everywhere
还一直到处找你
Let's go
快走吧
Your father is waiting for you
你爸爸在等你
Thank you for your hard work
辛苦你了
I don't have to worry about the driver who caused the accident, right?
我不必担心肇事司机吧
I've handled it perfectly
我已经完美地处理好了
you don't have to worry
您不用担心
Li Douxue seems to be here
李斗学好像来了
what to do
该怎么办
In case Li Douxue is detained
万一李斗学被拘留
Currently ongoing projects
目前正在进行的都更事业
will be greatly affected
就会大受影响
Big brother
大哥
Douxue
斗学
Your dad...
你爸爸…
Your father is so pitiful
你爸爸太可怜了
what to do
怎么办
Dad is so pitiful
爸爸太可怜了
You girl
你这丫头
Why are you coming back now?
为什么现在才回来
why
为什么
Your father has been waiting for you for a long time
你爸爸等了你很久
sorry dad You girl...
对不起 爸爸 你这丫头…
You...your father has been waiting for you for a long time
你…你爸爸等了你很久
Your dad...
你爸爸…
Tetsuo
哲雄
You also come out and give a grand ceremony
你也出来行大礼
Together with my brother and Zhenyu
跟哥哥还有贞玉一起
good
好
Douxue
斗学
Tetsuo
哲雄
Actually…
其实…
Take uncle...
把叔叔…
Buried in the ancestral grave of the Cui family
葬在崔家的祖坟吧
What...
什么…
Yes
是啊
uncle…
叔叔…
Just like the elders in our family
就像我们家里的长辈
I also agree with what my mother said I hope to do that too
我也同意我妈说的 我也希望那么做
No matter what, it’s still not good...
再怎么说还是不太好吧…
We owe him a lifetime of favors
我们欠了他一辈子的人情
At least use this method
至少用这个方法
Let's make it up to him
让我们弥补他吧
That way…
那样…
It’s also better for young people
对年轻人们也比较好
Relatives around me are passing away one after another
身边的亲人们接二连三地离世
The children should be very busy too
孩子们应该也忙得不可开交
No
不可以
My father will take care of him even after he dies. Are you from the Cui family?
我爸爸连死后都要伺候 崔家的人吗
Brother
哥
what are you talking about
你在说什么
Even if dad left a last word and said he wanted to do that
就算爸留下遗言说想那么做
I absolutely disagree
我也绝对不同意
That's not what we meant
我们又不是那种意思
why do you do this
你何必这样
Brother
哥
Zhenyu
贞玉
are you okay
你还好吗
sister
姊姊
I'm so scared
我好害怕
It's okay
没事的
It'll be okay
不会有事的
Damn it
该死
You are here
您来啦
I can't come in person
老爷没办法亲自来
He asked me to convey my regrets to you
他要我向你传达遗憾之情
Why not be careful?
怎么不小心点
It seems that your communication with the prosecutor something went wrong
看来您跟检察官的沟通 出了点问题
Please handle it as soon as possible
请您尽快处理
I received the report There is already a conclusion above
我收到报告 上头已经有结论了
thank you
谢谢
No…
不…
The top brass of the prosecutor's office heard that you were The head of the mafia organization
检察厅的高层听到你是 黑道组织的首脑时
Seems reluctant to let you go
似乎不太愿意放你
The establishment of the Loyalty Association was a big failure
成立忠义会是个大败笔
Because people regard the Loyalty Association
因为人们把忠义会
Think of it as being like other mafia organizations in the country
想成和国内其他黑道组织一样
You should be judged first
你先接受审判吧
what
什么
leader of a criminal group Can the sentence be life imprisonment or death?
犯罪集团的首脑 能判到无期或死刑吗
Yes that's right
对 没错
But…
不过…
Except that career is a problem
除了都更事业是个问题
Also we can’t be sure about Lee Doo Hak
还有我们无法确定李斗学
Will silence be maintained during the trial?
在审判过程中是否会保持沉默
Prosecutor Choi said he wanted to arrest him Let's support him
崔检察官说想抓他 我们就支持他吧
We also owe him a favor
我们也欠了他人情
Deputy Chief… This is my son's business
次长… 这是我儿子的事
So…
那么…
I will expose the illegal behavior of the Loyalty Association
我会把忠义会的非法行为
They got rid of Lian Guangzhuo
他们除掉廉光卓
And the inside story of the underworld struggle
还有黑道斗争的内幕
Tell the media everything
通通告诉媒体
That's it
就这样吧
It's not just spies we want to catch
我们要抓的不只是间谍
We also have the obligation to purify society
我们也有净化社会的义务
And…
而且…
Maybe it will be over before the trial.
说不定在庭审前就能结束
After all…
毕竟…
Anything can happen in a detention center
在拘留所里什么事都可能发生
Revenge from enemies on the road
被道上的冤家报复
or commit suicide
或是自杀
I will find an opportunity to bail you out during the process
我会在过程中找时机保释你
you don't have to worry
你不用担心
You are now…
您现在…
Are you trying to sell me out?
是想出卖我吗
betray
出卖
Didn't you say we want you to die? Are you going to die?
你不是说我们要你去死 你就会去死吗
This is a very important period in my life
现在是我人生中很重要的时期
my father passed away
我爸爸去世了
And I'm getting married soon please help me
而且我马上就要结婚了 请帮帮我
After that…
之后…
If you want me to die, I will definitely die.
你们要我死 我一定去死
We don't have a future
我们可没有之后
Why don't you put off your important things to a later date?
不如你把你重要的事往后延吧
Team leader
组长
Don't think too much
你不要想太多了
What? Is there no way?
什么 没有办法吗
Should you say this now?
你现在该说这种话吗
The method is found by people
办法是人找出来的
He had a hard time getting it Live an ordinary life
他好不容易才要 过上平凡人的生活
Do you want to watch him hit rock bottom again?
你要眼睁睁看他又跌到谷底吗
Not like that
不是那样的
Dingchen
定辰
This matter was decided by the superiors.
这件事是上级下定决心要办的
No matter what the investigation reveals, it doesn't matter
无论调查出什么都不重要
Because the result is a foregone conclusion
因为结果已成定局了
Have you heard of the Sanqing Education Team?
你听过三清教育队吧
The superiors plan to imitate the Sanqing Education Team
上级打算效仿三清教育队
The boss of the gang Achieve the effect of social purification
扫荡帮派的大老 达到社会净化的功效
Whether you want to get married or not is not the point now.
现在你要不要结婚不是重点
Brother Dou Xue will be imprisoned for at least ten years.
斗学哥他最少会被关十年
You might be sentenced to life imprisonment. Even the death penalty
搞不好会被处以无期徒刑 甚至是死刑
what
什么
This is not something I can interfere with
这不是我能插手的事
So didn’t I tell you?
所以我不是跟你说过了吗
You can't marry Brother Douxue
你不能跟斗学哥结婚
you will definitely get hurt
你绝对会受到伤害
This matter...
这件事…
It wasn't your plan, was it?
不会是你计划的吧
Do you think I'm that mean?
你认为我有那么卑鄙吗
Me too
我也一样
I've asked everything I can.
能打听的全都打听过了
if i had the ability
要是我有能力
I also want to save Brother Dou
我也想救斗学哥
Then go save him
那你就去救他
We must save him by any means
无论用任何手段都要救他
Douxue's father passed away
斗学的爸爸过世了
Zhenyu was detained by the police again
贞玉又被警察拘留
Did you also see your aunt's state just now?
你刚刚也看到伯母的状态了吧
It doesn't matter if I don't get married
我不结婚也没关系
But you must rescue Douxue
但你一定要把斗学救出来
Otherwise I will never see you in my life
不然我一辈子都不会见你
How could so many things happen at once...
怎么会一下子发生那么多事…
The boss of each branch of the Loyalty Association All were arrested
忠义会各分会的老大 全都被逮捕了
We should also avoid the limelight.
我们也该避避风头吧
The superiors also let go and let the prosecutors take action.
上级也松手让检方动作了
Feeling like something is fishy
感觉事有蹊跷
Douxue will go to jail again this time You will definitely not be able to get out.
斗学这次要是再度入狱 就绝对出不来了
We have to rescue him
要把他救出来才行
I think so too
我也这么觉得
what to do
那该怎么做
The spies are watching him with their eyes wide open.
条子们可是睁大眼睛在监视他耶
no matter what means We have to rescue him
无论用什么手段 都要把他救出来
Xuanyu and I will find a way
我跟宣宇会想办法
Don't interfere
你不要插手
Can you think of any method with your brains?
凭你们的脑袋能想出什么方法吗
Does it have to be you?
难道就非你不可吗
sorry
抱歉
You go quickly
你们快去吧
thank you
谢谢你
We just came back from our honeymoon
我们才刚度完蜜月回来
If you are caught by a police officer
你要是被条子抓到
Just waiting to die by my hands
就等着死在我手上
Don't worry, I don't want to die in your hands
别担心 我可不想死在你手上
(Lee Jong-ho)
(故李钟昊)
"I'm leaving. I'm leaving."
"我要走了 我要离开了"
"Holding my young son's hand"
"握着年幼儿子的手"
Douxue, dad is in a good mood today
斗学 爸今天心情很好
The teacher keeps praising you Say I taught you well
老师不断称赞你 说我把你教得很好
Old man, you really worked hard
老头子 你真的辛苦了
Never be reincarnated as a long-term worker in your next life
下辈子绝对不要投胎当长工
You must be reincarnated as a child of a rich family
一定要投胎成为有钱人家的孩子
Have a good trip…
一路好走…
This is already a great honor to you.
这样已经算是很给你面子了
I know but...
我知道 但是…
Can you let him finish lunch with his family before leaving?
能不能让他跟家人吃完午餐再走
No, I have to leave immediately
不行 要马上离开
The chief of Nanshan said this guy is dangerous
南山的长官说这家伙很危险
Nothing can go wrong
不能出任何差错
There will be some commotion later
等一下会有点骚动
Just run to the top of the hill in the direction of two o'clock.
你就往两点方向的山头跑去
uncle
大叔
Come here
你过来
Come here, you brat Don't you drive well?
你给我过来 臭小子 不好好开车吗
Oh, you brat...
唉唷 你这臭小子…
Brat
臭小子
Damn...
可恶…
catch that kid
抓住那小子
Douxue
斗学
catch him
抓住他
Wait a minute...
等一下…
catch him…
抓住他…
stop
停下来
let's go
我们走吧
Don't drive away. I'm not in the car yet.
不要开走 我还没上车
I will send him abroad
我会把他送到国外
what are you talking about
你在说什么
Are you crazy? Are you out of your mind?
你疯了吗 脑袋不正常了吗
Dingchen, think about it carefully
定辰 你好好想想
if you intervene
要是你插手
If you're not careful, something could happen to you too
一不小心 连你也会出事的
I will figure out how to deal with those later.
那些我之后会再想办法处理
The most important thing now is to rescue Douxue first.
现在最重要的是要先救出斗学啊
Do you want to rescue Douxue first?
要先救出斗学吗
What about me?
那我呢
what should i do
我要怎么办
Why should I risk my life to save him?
我为什么要赌上自己的命救他
Don't say it's because he and I are friends
你可别说因为我跟他是朋友喔
Tetsuo, no one can predict the future.
哲雄 未来的事谁也说不准
I promise you I will bet my life on the future save you once
我答应你 未来我会赌上生命 救你一次
Just take him to the port No matter what, let him sneak away
你们就把他带到港口 无论如何 让他偷渡离开
Douxue wouldn't want to do this
斗学不会想这样做的
No time now
现在没时间了
Why are you so hungry?
肚子怎么这么饿
Would you like a bowl of soup and rice?
你要不要吃碗汤饭呢
let me think
让我想想
Captain, I paid more than originally agreed. More
船长 我放得比原先说好的金额 还要多
Sorry to trouble you
麻烦您了
There's no time now. This is the only way.
现在没时间了 只有这个方法
The other person is a boatman I met when I was making a movie.
对方是我拍电影时认识的船夫
He owes me a favor, so he will definitely help me
他欠我人情 所以一定会帮我
"my love"
"我的爱"
"No matter where you are"
"无论身在何方"
"Please take good care of yourself Goodbye"
"请务必好好照顾自己 Goodbye"
"Our time to shine"
"我们闪耀的时节"
"will become eternity"
"将化作永恒"
"Please remember"
"请你记得"
sorry
抱歉
He won't take the road prepared for him
帮他准备好的路他不走
He is indeed that kind of person
他的确是那样的人
I'll take care of this myself
我会亲自处理这件事
Just wait and see
再等等看吧
That person Li Douxue
李斗学那个人
You should be prepared and contact us again.
应该会有所准备再跟我们联络
If the prosecutor wants to arrest you, forget it.
检方那边要逮捕你就算了
But there was nothing wrong with the process of passing on the secret funds.
但传递秘密资金的过程又没出错
Confidentiality is kept tight
保密也做得滴水不漏
Plus you haven’t gone against them before.
加上你又没跟他们作对过
Where can I find a loyal dog like you?
上哪里找像你这种忠犬
How could they suddenly abandon you?
他们怎么会突然抛弃你
Is it because of Lian Guangzhuo?
是因为廉光卓吗
not him
不是他
He fled to the United States a long time ago
他很久以前就逃到美国了
Prosecutor Park Ji-hwan and Choi Cheol-woong Is a concurrent student of the Judicial Examination
朴志焕检察官跟崔哲雄 是司法考试的同期生
But if he wants to catch me There's no reason to help me unlock my handcuffs.
但他如果想抓我 没理由帮我解开手铐吧
Besides...
再说…
The biggest handle in his life is in my hands
他人生最大的把柄在我手上
In short, if the people over there in Nanshan abandon you, This is the only way
总之南山那边的人如果抛弃你 就只有这个方法了
Let's get on this boat and sneak to Japan.
坐上这艘船偷渡到日本去吧
After arriving in Japan…
到日本之后…
Whether it's smuggling or going to jail
无论是偷渡或坐牢
I'll lose everything anyway
反正我都会失去一切
Is it possible that you want to fight against them?
难不成你要跟他们对干吗
You wake up
你清醒点
not just us
不只是我们
Dingchen also bet on his life Want to help you sneak across
定辰也赌上自己的人生 要帮助你偷渡
if you get caught Dingchen will also become a criminal
要是你被抓到 定辰也会变成罪犯
Her life is ruined
她的人生就毁了
So say
所以说啊
To restore everything to its original state
要让一切恢复原状
Only then can we find a stable life
才能找回安稳的生活
Hello Li Douxue
喂 李斗学
Douxue
斗学
secret money ledger
秘密资金帐簿
If this is made public to the world
要是把这个公诸于世
Those guys should have been hit hard too.
那些家伙受到的打击应该也不小
But if they don't want to negotiate with you It's not as simple as going to jail
但要是他们不想跟你谈判 就不是坐牢这么简单了
They'll cut you off by the roots.
他们会斩草除根把你除掉
Just hide first
就先躲起来吧
Let's accumulate strength
我们好好蓄积实力
Then give them a fatal blow
之后给他们致命一击
Brother
哥
I experienced two near-death escapes Just got here
我经历了两次的死里逃生 才走到这里
Are you lucky?
运气很好吧
No matter how lucky you are I've never heard of anyone escaping death three times.
你运气再怎么好 我也没听过有人死里逃生三次的
but i want to try
但我想要试试看
Douxue
斗学
Big brother
大哥
The man who killed your father turned himself in
撞死你爸的人自首了
It's a guy named Lee Yongdeok
是个叫做李勇得的家伙
Has four previous convictions
有四项前科
Includes violence, fraud and gambling
包括暴力 诈欺和赌博
He was driving while fatigued
他当时是疲劳驾驶
He said he had no idea he was causing the accident
说根本不知道自己肇事
We have called brothers Went to investigate his background.
我们已经叫兄弟们 去调查他的背景了
The most amazing thing is…
最惊人的是…
Choi Cheol-woong’s mother is getting remarried
崔哲雄他妈妈要再婚了
The person she remarried was Huang Zhongcheng
她再婚的对象是黄忠诚
what did you say
你说什么
hello
喂 你好
I am Li Douxue
我是李斗学
Do you think you are making a movie?
你以为自己在拍电影啊
what is the reason
理由是什么
I told you, things have gotten too big.
我说过了 事情已经闹太大了
I can't let you Affects the work of our unit
可不能让你们 影响到我们单位的工作
But you are obviously capable of solving this matter
但这件事你们明明就有能力解决
What is the real reason?
真正的理由到底是什么
You are so suspicious
你的疑心病真重
It's not okay for a hound to think too much.
猎犬想太多可不行
I sent a package
我寄了一个包裹过去
Let’s have a serious discussion with your master.
跟你们家老爷好好讨论一下吧
I will contact you again
我会再跟你联络
(Gongchangdong has more subscription money) Secret financial ledger?
(功长洞都更认购款项) 秘密资金帐簿吗
Didn't I say you can't keep this kind of document?
我不是说过不能留下这种文件吗
sorry
抱歉
I'm having a wedding this week
这周我就要举行婚礼了
Things need to be properly handled before this happens
在这之前要把事情确实处理好
Be sure to get the original account books back
一定要把帐簿正本找回来
I know
我知道了
We sent investigators and police Tracked everyone he might contact.
我们派了搜查官和警察 跟踪了所有他可能会联络的人
But the whereabouts of key figures could not be found
但都查不到关键人物的行踪
That group of people can be said to be one and the same.
那群人可以说是一体同心
When you were catching Li Douxue The others should be arrested together
你在抓李斗学时 应该把其他人一起抓起来的
Didn't I tell you before?
我之前不是跟你说过了吗
Sorry
抱歉啦
But how on earth did that guy unlock the handcuffs?
但那家伙到底是怎么解开手铐的
We found Li Douxue
我们找到李斗学了
are you dissatisfied
你不满意吗
No
没有
very beautiful
很漂亮
thank you
谢谢你
Did you listen to Prosecutor Choi?
你听崔检察官说了吗
I heard Douxue escaped
听说斗学逃走了
I heard Douxue’s mother said that
我听斗学她妈说了
She also asked me if I could help Bang Douxue
她还问我能不能帮帮斗学
what
什么
I know it's shameless to ask you like this
我知道这样拜托您很厚颜无耻
But Douxue’s father passed away like that
但斗学的爸就那样过世
If something happens to even Douxue
如果连斗学都出事的话
I really have no confidence that I can survive
我真的没有信心能活下去
I understand
我明白
I understand your mood better than anyone else
我比任何人还了解你的心情
But…
不过…
This is not something I can help with
这不是我能帮上忙的事
A wanted criminal who has committed a serious crime and is on the run.
犯了重罪又逃亡的通缉犯
How can I save him from punishment?
我怎么有办法让他免于刑罚呢
i know
我知道
If you make a mistake, you should be punished
犯错就该接受惩罚
I mean
我的意思是
Laws are made by people
法律是人制定的
Judges and prosecutors are human beings too
法官跟检察官也是人
It should be a little more humane.
应该有点人情味吧
It was a crime that was originally going to be punished by the top ten
本来要打十大板的罪
Can it be changed to playing five big boards?
也能改成打五大板嘛
But a peasant woman like me
但像我这种农妇
Even if you ask for mercy No one will pay attention to me
就算去求情 一定也不会有人理我
If the gentleman next to my wife
如果夫人身旁的那位老爷
Say something to Douxue
帮斗学说句话
Maybe those officials will listen.
那些官员说不定会听进去啊
You may not know clearly
你可能不太清楚
But the more senior public officials are
但越是身处高位的公职人员
The less likely you are to ask for help or make excuses
就越不能进行请托或关说
Something will happen if you do this
这么做会出事
It will also make it difficult for him
也会让他很为难
How could I not want to help?
我怎么可能不想帮忙呢
If you can help
如果能够帮忙
Whatever you want me to do I can't deny it
无论要我做什么都行 我一定义不容辞
But it's really not possible to do this
但是这样做真的不行
Madam, please help me
夫人 拜托您帮忙
as long as you help
只要您帮忙
You want me to pull out all my hair I can knit it into shoes for you
要我把头发全拔下来 编成鞋子给您都行
What if something goes wrong in Douxue?
如果斗学出了什么差错
How can I survive
要我怎么活下去
Please, madam, please help me once.
拜托夫人您帮我一次吧
Just help me once
帮我一次就好
Although I sympathize with you But there's nothing I can do
虽然我很同情你 但我也无能为力
Get up quickly
你快起来吧
Really not possible?
真的不行吗
yes
是的
We fight to learn...
我们斗学…
He and Tetsuo are brothers whose blood is thicker than water.
跟哲雄是血浓于水的亲兄弟
Can't you help me?
这样你也不能帮忙吗
A studious mother
斗学的妈
After I give the child to you
我把孩子给您之后
I've never asked you for help, right?
从来都没拜托过您帮忙吧
Did you have to mention that?
你非得要提到那件事吗
I can do anything now
我现在什么事都做得出来
Do you want me to go to Tetsuo to beg for mercy?
要我去找哲雄求情吗
A studious mother Do you really want to do this?
斗学的妈 你真的要做到这一步吗
So please...
所以拜托您…
Please help me this time
拜托您帮我这一次吧
Please...
拜托您…
I know
我知道了
If Douxue is investigated by the prosecutor
如果斗学接受检方的调查
I will intercede for him then.
到时我会帮他说情看看
thank you
谢谢您
thank you very much
真的很谢谢您
But don't have high expectations
但你不要抱太大的期待
Even if you just say a word for him I will also be grateful
就算您只帮他说一句话 我也会感激不尽
thank you very much
真的很感谢您
Also
还有
Please never mention Tetsuo again
请你再也不要提到哲雄的事
Okay, it's all my fault
好 都是我的错
I will never mention it again
我绝对不会再提起
So what do you want me to do
所以你希望我怎么做
Do you want me to help Li Dou learn?
你希望我帮李斗学吗
I hope…
我希望…
can you help
你能帮忙
But only about our son
但只限于我们儿子的事
Didn't he hide after he escaped?
他逃走之后不是躲起来
Do you want to risk your life to negotiate?
而是赌上性命想进行谈判吗
What's the deputy chief's idea?
次长的想法呢
The deputy chief will not compromise with the hound.
次长他不会向猎犬妥协的
Where is Wu Dingchen?
吴定辰呢
Never lose Wu Dingchen
绝对不要把吴定辰跟丢
Li Douxue will definitely appear in front of Wu Dingchen
李斗学一定会出现在吴定辰面前
"i love you"
"我爱你"
"I should say this"
"我应该把这句话说出口"
"Without you"
"如果没有你"
"I can't survive"
"我就活不下去"
(Let’s pretend to be crazy while drinking to drive the police away) "i love you"
(借酒装疯去把警察赶走吧) "我爱你"
"I should say this"
"我应该把这句话说出口"
"Hesitated and didn't say anything"
"犹豫着没说出口"
"You will leave me"
"你便离我而去"
You two have worked really hard.
两位真是辛苦了
Monitor me all day
一整天都在监视我
what are you talking about
你在说什么
You seem to have the wrong person
你好像认错人了
Do you think I'm a fool?
把我当笨蛋吗
waiter
服务生
Serve me wine
帮我上酒
I'll treat you to a drink
我请你们喝
Is this lady drunk?
这位小姐喝醉了吧
Who is drunk?
谁喝醉啦
Do you know the whereabouts of Li Douxue?
你们知道李斗学的下落吗
I'm so curious too
我也好奇死了
If you know, just tell me
知道的话 就跟我说嘛
I'm having a wedding soon
我快要办婚礼了
The groom has to be there
新郎要到场才行啊
Will he come or not?
究竟他会不会来呢
Let's make a bet
我们来打赌吧
Uncle, which side do you want to bet on?
大叔 你要赌哪一边
Miss, are you crazy?
小姐 你疯了吧
Yeah, I'm crazy
对啊 我疯了
If it were you, wouldn't you go crazy?
换作是你们 难道不会发疯吗
Damn...
该死的…
What's wrong
怎么了
Come follow me Didn't you expect to be caught by me?
你们来跟踪我 都没想到会被我抓到吗
what are you doing
你这是在干嘛
Come out quickly
快出来
come out with me
跟我出来
You all come out
你们都给我出来
I'm going to beat you to death with nunchucks
我要用双节棍揍死你们
Sorry, she seems too drunk.
抱歉 她好像喝得太醉了
sorry
抱歉
Did Li Dou learn to come here? Cheers to me?
难道李斗学会跑来这里 跟我干杯吗
where are you going
你们要去哪里
Come out with me
快跟我出来
Where are you going?
你们到底要去哪里
You are really...
你真是的…
If you want to follow me, just follow me to the end.
你们要跟踪我 就跟踪到底嘛
You've had enough
你够了喔
They're gone, you don't have to act anymore
他们走了 你可以不用演了
Yeon Joo
妍珠
Douxue wants me to take you there safely
斗学要我把你平安带过去
what
什么
He's super romantic
他超浪漫的
Don't think it's like Hollywood movie plot?
不觉得这就像是 好莱坞的电影情节吗
Now is not the time to joke
现在不是开玩笑的时候
Yoko What's wrong
阳子 怎么了
Is there a backdoor here?
这里有后门吗
Of course over there
当然 在那边
Come with me
快跟我走吧
Dingchen
定辰
Yeon Joo
妍珠
Hyung Soo
亨洙
Of course I want a kiss
当然要亲一下了
Why didn't you leave and still stayed here?
你怎么没有离开 还留在这里
Where can I go if you are here?
你人在这里 我又能去哪里呢
you are crazy
你疯了
You should leave quickly before you get caught.
要在被抓到之前快离开才对啊
We agreed
我们说好了
To live a steady and ordinary life
要过着细水长流而平凡的生活
I still need to pick up the wedding dress.
还要去拿婚礼的礼服
can we really do it
我们真的能够做到吗
Of course
那当然
Yoko said I'm a crazy woman
阳子说我是个疯女人
It seems she is right
看来她说得没错
I'm probably a lunatic too
我大概也是个疯子吧
Hey let's go...
喂 我们走吧…
Let's go
走吧
You should listen carefully to what I say now
我现在说的话 你要仔细听好
I have the secret fund account book of the Ministry of Security and Enterprise
我手上有安企部的秘密资金帐簿
As long as that document is made public...
只要那份文件被公诸于世…
Hello…
喂…
Li Douxue raised his hands and knelt down
李斗学 举起双手跪下
Douxue
斗学
Come on, raise your hands and kneel down
快点举起双手跪下
Hey you guys...
喂 你们这群家伙…
Dingchen
定辰
I don't want
我不要
Dingchen, I’m begging you
定辰 我拜托你了
Come on, raise your hands and kneel down
快点举起双手跪下
Let go
快放手
No one is allowed to move
全都不许动
Please stop
拜托你停手
everything is over
一切都已经结束了
Yes
是啊
Why is Choi Cheol-woong missing here?
这里怎么少得了崔哲雄呢
I heard your mother remarried to someone
听说你妈再婚的对象
It's Huang Zhongcheng
是黄忠诚啊
It all makes sense now
现在一切都说得通了
I was really curious before
我之前真的很好奇
As expected, it's you who is doing the trick
果不其然 就是你在搞鬼
Don't talk nonsense
你不要胡说八道
These two things have nothing to do with each other
这两件事完全无关
Just stop it
你就停手吧
If you stop
停手的话
Will you go to jail in my place?
你会代替我吃牢饭吗
Just like before I took your place...
就像以前我代替你…
Let go of the hostages
放开人质
Otherwise I will really shoot you
不然我真的会对你开枪
"Can I come back to you again?"
"我能再回到你身边吗"
"trembling eyes"
"颤抖的眼神"
"Looks more sad"
"显得更加哀戚"
"My heart is swaying in the desolate sky" No
"我的心在荒凉的天空中飘摇" 不可以
"your name"
"你的名字"
"It's deeply etched in my heart"
"深深刻在我心上"
"Where did it all go wrong?"
"从哪里开始出错的"
"I don't know"
"我不知道"
"It's useless to talk too much anyway"
"反正多说无益"
"It's all in the past"
"都是过去的事了"
(Preview of next episode)
(下集预告)
I only have you now
我现在只有你了
I plan to let Prosecutor Cui meet my daughter.
我打算让崔检察官跟小女见个面
Wu Dingchen probably won’t be attending this year.
今年吴定辰应该不会出席了
What happened in Dingchen?
定辰发生什么事了吗
I did as the lady said
我照夫人说的话去做了
Thank you for your hard work
辛苦您了
Why don't you marry Tetsuo?
你跟哲雄结婚吧
It’s time to let go of those who left
该放下离开的人了
Those who are alive should continue to live their lives.
活着的人要继续过日子啊
Does the Minister also know about Prosecutor Choi’s marriage?
崔检察官的婚事 部长也知情吗
Special assistant to the Minister of Security and Enterprise?
安企部长的特别辅佐官吗
Just think of it as doing something for me
你就当作是帮我做事吧
What is the important secret code?
重要的密令是什么